Tonight, we've come to Tokyo Tower in Minato District.
今晚我们来到了位于港区的东都塔
Here at the Tokyo Tower, the Tanabata Fair is currently underway,
由于东都塔正在举行七夕祭典
attracting a large number of visitors...
因此现场迎来了大批游客…
Yeah, I know.
啊 知道了啦
Meet at the professor's at 4:00 p.m., right?
4点到博士家是吧 元太你才是呢
Don't be late. See you!
可别迟到了哦 再见
I also need a flashlight.
还有手电筒
Well, I remember it was...
嗯 我记得是…
in this drawer.
在这个抽屉里的
Ah! Here it is!
啊 找到了
Huh?
嗯？
Who's there? Ran-neechan?
谁？ 小兰姐姐？
Mr. Mouri is out playing mahjong. It can't be him.
大叔去打麻将了应该不在家
Huh...Must be my imagination!
哈…是心理作用吧
Long time no see, Shinichi Kudo! Or...
好久不见了啊 工藤新一 不
should I call you Conan Edogawa?
现在是江户川柯南吧
I'm surprised that you are still alive, and as a kid!
真没想到你居然变成了个小孩继续活着
Hell of a miracle, isn't it, Boss?
真是的 真令人吃惊啊 大哥
How... How did they find out my identity?
为什么 为什么我的真实身份会…
Conan-kun?
柯南
Conan-kun, what's going on?
柯南 怎么了
I heard some loud noises down there.
怎么那么大的声音啊
Conan-kun?
柯南
Look carefully.
好好看着
Look and see how everyone
和你扯上关系的人
around you will end up!
都会步入怎样的命运之路
Conan-kun? Is everything okay?
柯南 没事吧
Conan-kun?
柯南
Are you inside?
在里面吗
I'm coming in.
我进来了哦
Conan-kun?
柯南
Ran!
小兰
Holy crap! What a nightmare!
可恶 居然做这种梦
I'm high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
While visiting an amusement park
一次我和青梅竹马的
with Ran Mouri, my childhood friend and classmate,
同学毛利兰去游乐园玩的时候
I witnessed a man in black in the middle of a suspicious deal.
目击了黑衣男子可疑的交易现场
Totally caught up in watching the deal go down,
由于太过专注于交易
I failed to notice one of his partners sneaking up behind me.
没有注意到从我身后靠近的另一个同伙
It was then that he forced me to take some weird drug.
我被他强行灌下了毒药
When I woke up again,
等我醒来的时候
my body had shrunk to that of a child!
身体竟然变小了
If those guys found out that I was still alive,
如果让那些家伙发现工藤新一还活着
they'd come after me again
不仅会自身难保
and put those around me at risk.
还会危及到身边的人
At Professor Agasa's suggestion,
在阿笠博士的建议下
I hid my real identity,
我决定隐藏自己的真实身份
and came up with the alias Conan Edogawa
当小兰问起我名字时 我急中生智
when pressed by Ran.
称自己为江户川柯南
In order to collect information on those responsible,
为了搜集那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran, whose father is a detective.
我寄住进了父亲是侦探的小兰家
The mysterious Black Organization consists of
谜团重重的黑衣人组织
Gin,
Gin
Vodka,
Vodka
Vermouth,
Vermouth
Chianti, Korn,
Chianti…Korn
and Sherry.
还有Sherry
Her real name is Shiho Miyano.
她的真名叫宫野志保
Her parents, who died when she was young, once served as scientists for the Black Organization.
在她年幼时去世的父母曾是黑衣组织的专属科学家
Under the codename Sherry,
她以Sherry这个代号
she also worked for the Organization,
为那伙人效力
and developed the aforementioned drug APTX4869.
让我缩小的药 APTX4869就是由她开发
However, when her only elder sister, Akemi Miyano, was killed by the Organization,
但是 由于唯一的姐姐宫野明美被他们杀害
she turned against them.
她便开始反抗组织
She took the drug with the intention of taking her own life,
本想就此了结性命的她吞下了那种药后
but instead, her body shrank as well.
身体也变小了
She thus changed her name to Ai Haibara,
就这样 现在更名为灰原哀
disguising herself as a first grader like I have
一边逃避组织的追踪
in order to evade the Organization.
一边和我一样就读小学一年级
Meanwhile, in one of my encounters with Vermouth,
其中 在和Vermouth的对决中
I found an important lead.
我发现了一条线索
I wouldn't if I were you.
住手吧
If you attempt to unplug this device, a signal will be sent to my partner.
要是你拔掉的话 我的同伴就会接到信号
With your boss's...
得到你们BOSS的…
E-mail address.
邮箱地址哦
S-Seven Children?
七…七子之歌？
Yeah. When you input the boss's address, that's what it sounds like...
嗯 BOSS的邮箱地址的按键音听起来就是…
The melody of Seven Children.
童谣「七子之歌」
Don't tell me you are going to send an E-mail.
你该不会要发邮件过去吧
No way! I'm not that stupid, okay?
怎么可能 我会那么蠢吗
I won't send one until Detective Takagi finds out who owns this E-mail address...
我要先等高木刑警查到谁在用这个邮箱之后再…
He'll be killed. I mean Detective Takagi.
会被干掉的 我说高木刑警
It'll happen when he gets close to finding out.
就在他快要查到那个人物的时候
And their next target will be the one who provided him with the address, which would be you, Kudo-kun.
接着他们就会将矛头指向提供地址的工藤你了
I say, you should let it go and forget all about it.
我劝你还是赶紧放弃 忘了这件事吧
Because that E-mail address
因为 那个邮箱地址是…
is like a Pandora's Box that should never be opened.
绝对不能打开的 潘多拉之盒
Even though my body has shrunk, I'm still the same sharp-minded,
身体虽然变小 头脑依旧灵活
intelligent, and undefeated detective!
无所不通的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
Oh, there you are!
喂 有了有了
Nice!
好嘞
I found one! A beetle!
找到了 锹形甲虫
Well done!
成功啦
So it's true that those beetles like to stay in high places.
果然锹形甲虫是在上面的啊
Alright! I'll climb up there too!
好 我也要爬
I don't think so, Genta-kun.
你不行的元太
You'd better not.
你还是放弃吧
I agree.
就是啊
Besides Edogawa-kun, the only ones that can climb that high are monkeys.
能爬上那么高的地方的 也就只有江户川同学和猴子之类的了
Excuse me for being a monkey...
我这只猴子真是对不住你了…
I know! You can use the suspenders.
对了 用伸缩式背带就行了
Suspenders?
伸缩式背带？
Oh. You mean those things you gave us earlier?
就是这个吧 刚才在你家拿的
Yes. I've improved them.
是的 我做了下改进
One push of that button will make it extend up to 100 meters.
只要按一下按钮就可以在百米内自由伸缩了
If you hold the button down, the belt will keep elongating.
一直按着的话就会一直伸长
Once you release it and press again, the belt will retract immediately.
再按一下的话就会快速地缩回来了
Ouch!
…好痛
I'm... I'm sorry!
对…对不起
Come on! Be careful!
真是的 你当心点嘛
I found a beetle!
发现锹形甲虫了
That's great, Genta-kun.
太好了 元太
A rhinoceros beetle!
是独角仙
There's another one!
那里还有
Wow, two of them!
哇 有两只呢
A male and a female!
一只雄的一只雌的呢
Eh?
咦？
The female beetle's wings have been taped. Look!
这个雌的独角仙 前翅上贴着胶带呢 快看
It's true. So mean!
真的呢 太过分了
Something's written on it.
好像写着什么字呢
Let's see...
这个嘛…
Oh, it says "open."
啊 那是OPEN啊
They use this kind of tape on bento boxes sold in convenience stores.
大概是便利店卖的便当上经常贴着的那种吧
I saw some on a fried chicken bento I bought yesterday...
昨天买的炸鸡便当上也有…
Fried chicken?
炸鸡？
Isn't your belly big enough?
你就等着肚子越来越大吧
Let me see. I'll get those off.
让我看看 我来弄下来
Oh. Sure.
啊 好
Who did this? What an awful prank!
是谁搞的这种恶作剧啊
But, since there are a male and a female,
不过 既然有雄有雌
maybe
说不定
they are lovers.
它们是恋人吧
Then Ayumi will name them.
那我来帮它们取个名字吧
Well...The male is called Hikoboshi, and the female, Orihime!
那个…男生就叫牛郎 女生叫织女
Good idea!
好名字啊
Now that you mentioned it, Tanabata festival is coming up.
这么一说 马上要到七夕了呢
Speaking of Tanabata...
说到七夕
Alright. It's off.
好了 拿下来了
...it's time for your long-waited quiz!
让大家久等的猜谜时间到了
No one was waiting for that...
谁等着了…
One year, on the night of Tanabata, it rained heavily,
有一年的七夕夜 由于下大雨
stopping Orihime and Hikoboshi from reaching one another.
织女和牛郎无法相会了
Troubled, the two lovers decided on a "Day to Spend with Your Lover,"
困扰的两人经过考虑 终于决定在“与恋人共度之日”
or "Lovers' Day" for short, so they could meet on that day instead.
简称“恋共日”时再私自会面
Now, which of the following is that day?
那么 这一天是下面的哪个呢
No. 1, New Year's Day on January 1st.
1. 一月一日·元旦
No. 2, Setsubun on February 2nd.
2. 二月二日左右·立春
No. 3, Peach Festival on March 3rd.
3. 三月三日·女儿节
No. 4, Tango no Sekku on May 5th.
4. 五月五日·端午节
I know! No. 3! Peach Festival!
我明白了 是第三个 女儿节吧
Because Odairi-sama and Ohina-sama are lovers in the girl's doll sets they sell then.
因为恋人就是男人偶和女人偶呀
Nope. It should be No. 4, Tango no Sekku.
不 是第四个 端午节
Because lovers like to dance to the passionate music of tango!
因为和恋人一起跳的舞应该是热情的探戈
I think it's No. 1! On New Year's Day, you can eat mochi with your lover!
我猜是第一个 元旦和恋人一起吃烩年糕
Oh, you guys sure came up with some good reasons.
哦 你们还真是想了蛮多的呢
Professor, what's the answer?
博士 谜底呢
It's No. 4, May 5th.
是第四个 五月五日
I got it right!
我猜对咯
But my explanation is...
但是 和我想的…
May 5th, also called Children's Day, can be read "Kodomo no Hi."
五月五日是“子供日”（儿童节）
If you separate the kanji from Kodomo no Hi,
分解“子供日”的话
you'll get "Ko-i-tomo-no-Hi", namely "Koi, tomo no Hi", or Lovers' Day.
就是“子（ko）-亻（i）-共日”也就是“恋（koi）共日”吧
I see, a pun!
原来如此
That's why you told us the shorter name for "Day to Spend with Your Lover", right?
所以你才特地将“与恋人共度之日”缩略的吧
"Lovers' Day," huh?
是“恋共日”啊
I hope that Hikoboshi-san and Orihime-san can be together forever!
要是这对牛郎和织女能永远在一起就好了
Say, do you really think it's suitable to name two beetles Hikoboshi and Orihime?
即便如此 本来把独角仙取名牛郎和织女就不合适嘛
Why not?
是吗
I think those are perfect names.
我倒觉得恰到好处呢
Orihime in English is Vega.
织女星的英文是Vega
The tape on the female beetle forms the letter "V,"
贴在那只雌独角仙上的标签
which is the first letter of Vega, isn't it?
可以看见它的第一个字母“V”吧
True! It is perfect!
真的呢 真是很合适呢
Yes!
嗯
Well done, Haibara-san!
不愧是灰原同学
Say, how am I supposed to get down?
那个 我要怎么下去呢
What's going on?
怎么回事 咦
Stop! Stop!
停下 停下
Hey! Are you okay?
喂 你没事吧
Call an ambulance!
喂 快叫救护车
Okay!
是
T-Tanabata...Kyo...
七…七夕… 京…
What?
什么
Hey! Hang in there! The ambulance will be here soon!
喂 坚持住 救护车马上就来了
Hey! Stay with me!
喂 喂 坚持住
Listen, I'm making an exception by bringing you here.
给我听好了 今天破例带你过来了
You need to behave yourself.
要老老实实呆着哦
Okay!
嗯
Ah, dad, your tie is crooked.
啊 爸爸 领带歪了
Ah, Mouri-san!
啊 毛利先生
Thank you for stopping by this early!
这么一大早的 辛苦了
Good morning, Ran-chan, Conan-kun.
早啊 小兰 柯南
Good morning!
早上好
So this is a full-on serial murder case?
听说是大范围的连续杀人啊
Yes. Our crime scene yesterday was on a turnpike in Odawara City.
是的 昨日在小田原市的收费高速上
We also found a mahjong tile there.
发生凶杀的现场发现了麻将牌
Similar mahjong tiles were also found at the previous crime scenes
同样的麻将牌也出现在了东京 神奈川
in Tokyo, Kanagawa, Shizuoka and Nagano.
静冈 长野等地区
There are altogether five similar cases now.
发生的5起案件中
I see.
原来如此
Anyway, let's go over the details in the meeting.
总之 详细情况开会再说
Please.
请
Hey, isn't that Mouri-san! Long time no see!
喂 这不是毛利先生吗 好久不见
You are as loud as always,
你还是一如既往的大嗓门啊
Yokomizo.
横沟
I'm Sango. This is my brother, Juugo.
我是参悟 这是我弟弟重悟
I know. I've met him several times.
我认识 见过好几次了
Sango and Juugo? Like, 3-5 and 10-5?
三…三五？ 十五？
Who's the lady?
那边的那位女性是？
Oh, pardon me. This is Inspector Ogino with the Saitama Prefecture Police.
忘介绍了 她是埼玉县警局的荻野警部
I'm Ayami Ogino. I've heard so much about you.
我叫荻野彩实 久闻大名了
My, to think there was such a beautiful inspector in the Saitama Prefecture Police!
呀 没想到埼玉县警局还有这么个美女警部啊
When I worked in Saitama, she was junior to me.
她是我在埼玉任职时候的后辈
Why the Saitama Prefecture Police?
埼玉县警局？
The victim who was killed in Tokyo was from Tokorozawa, Saitama,
因为在东京被杀的受害者住在所泽
so I was called to this meeting.
所以我才被叫来开会
And what brought you here, Mouri-san?
毛利先生又怎么会来这里
He was invited to serve as a special advisor as per Superintendent Matsumoto's request.
这次他是作为特别顾问来的 是松本管理官钦点的
To think we have to call upon a private detective for help. How shameful!
居然要向侦探求助 真是太不成体统了
Agreed.
同感
You are...
你好像是…
Inspector Yamato Kansuke from Nagano Prefecture Police. And you are
长野县警局的大和敢助警部 还有
that quack detective with Gunma prefecture Police...
群马县警局的笨蛋刑警…
You are such a kidder, Mouri-san!
您说笑了 毛利先生
You know my name is Yamamura Misao.
您不是知道我叫山村操的吗 瞧
But, didn't the incident happen in Nagano?
不过 案件是发生在长野县的吧
Why would someone from Gunma...
为什么群马县警会…
Because the crime scene lies on the border of Nagano and Gunma, so...
因为犯罪现场正好横跨长野和群马交界处 所以…
The victim's body parts from the knees down were in Gunma Prefecture! Right here!
这具弃尸从膝盖以下部分 是在群马县境内的 您看这个
Ah, enough, I already know your name.
哈？ 好了 你的名字我已经知道了啦
I-Inspector?
警…警部？
You were promoted to inspector?
你这家伙 升警部啦
Oh, you've noticed! It's true that I've been honorably promoted to inspector!
被您发现啦 托您的福我已经升职为警部了
So you were promoted...
你都升警部了啊
Is Gunma serious about this?
没问题吧 群马县警局…
Say, did the boy with glasses come?
话说 今天那个眼镜仔没来吗
The boy with glasses?
眼镜仔？
You mean Conan?
你是说柯南吗
Yes, Conan Edogawa-kun.
是啊 江户川柯南
When he's around, cases always seem to get solved easily.
只要他在的话 案件总能解决呢
Come to think of it, that's happened to me, too!
我那时好像也是这样呢
Same here as well!
我那时也是的
Ah? You all think so?
啊 大家都是这样的啊
Actually, we can't agree more!
事实上我们也是这样的
And then you'd lose consciousness,
后来 我突然就失去意识
and next thing you knew, the case was already solved, right?
不知不觉就把案件给解决了
Oops!
不妙
Lose consciousness?
失去意识？
Really?
真的吗
That didn't happen to me.
这个好像没有
Never. Never.
没有没有没有
What? Just me?
咦？只有我是这样的吗
You were the only officer I've ever tranquilized.
被我射过麻醉针的刑警 也就只有你了
How weird...
奇怪…
It's time for the meeting.
差不多该开会了
Excuse me!
啊 抱歉
Mouri-san!
毛利先生
Hey, Mouri-san!
喂 毛利先生
Huh?
啊？
Who is he? He looks so mean.
那是谁啊 那个一脸凶相的人
Idiot! That's Superintendent Kiyonaga Matsumoto!
笨蛋 那是管理官 松本清长警视
With a face like that?
啊 就那张脸？
Keep talking like that, and you'll get your ass kicked!
你那样说 会被扁的哦
For starters, putting the sixth case aside, the common factor between the previous five cases was
首先 除去第六件案件 其他五件共通的地方是
that all of the victims were stabbed to death with a large knife.
都是使用大型刀具的刺杀
Judging from the puncture wounds,
从伤口的形状来看
the killer raised his right arm and plunged the knife straight down.
都是用右手从上面挥落下来的
Also, the victims in each of the five cases were attacked with a stun gun first,
而且 五件的被害者都是先被凶手用电棒击昏
then killed and left at the primary crime scenes.
然后在尸体发现现场被杀害并被遗弃
Now, one question surfaces. Why did the suspect
这儿就有个疑问出现了 嫌疑犯为什么
move the disabled and unconscious victims to another location
要把已经失去意识的受害者特意搬到其他地方后
to complete the murder?
再杀害呢
Besides, on the bodies of the six victims
其次 在这六件案件的所有尸体上
we found mahjong tiles with red circles on the front
都发现了有红色圆印
and alphabet letters with black vertical lines through them on the back.
和背面写有拉丁字母和黑色纵线的麻将牌
These appear to be messages left by the killer.
这个很显然就是嫌疑犯留下的信息
About the red circles of the 7-pin tiles, the top-right
红色圆印中 七筒的下面四个圈圈中
and bottom-left circles of the four bottom ones are left unmarked.
右上和左下涂上的东西都没有了啊
The alphabet letters are two A's, E, H, Z and an upside-down L.
拉丁字母是两个A及E、H、Z 还有反着的L吗
Also, each one of the six victims has had something
而且 这六个被害者的随身携带物中
taken from among their belongings.
每个人都被拿走了一样东西
A pendant, a wallet, a keepsake...
项链吊坠 钱包 护身袋
A motorcycle key holder, a make-up kit, and a doll.
摩托车钥匙圈 还有化妆盒 吉祥人偶
Could they merely have fallen out while the bodies were being moved from one place to another?
会不会是在被害人被拖移的时候遗失的呢
No. Since each of the six victims had precisely one item missing,
不 如果是这六人中的每人一个的话
chances were they were taken by the suspect.
我还是认为应该是被嫌疑犯拿走的
Our main focus all comes down to the meaning of those messages.
重点果然在还是那个信息的意义上啊
There's another message.
信息还有一个
Our sixth victim, Ryuuzaki-san, said words "Tanabata...Kyo" before he died.
第六名被害人 龙崎留下的“七夕…京…”这个死亡讯息
Ryuuzaki-san was probably at the rest stop on Mount Daikan
那座被认为会耗尽最后一滴油的大锏山
when his brake oil ran out. It must also be the place where he saw the suspect.
龙崎也许就是在那里的休息站看到了嫌疑犯
Say... Everybody.
我说… 各位
No need to overcomplicate this case.
不用想得太过复杂吧
I think the mahjong tiles represent the game of mahjong itself.
麻将牌就是表示麻将牌
The motive is simple. It's an argument gone wrong over a game of mahjong.
杀人动机嘛就是围绕麻将而产生的纠纷
The 1-pin and 7-pin tiles left by the suspect
放置一筒和七筒2张牌
suggest that there were eight players.
意思就是8个人在打麻将
As for the 7-pin tiles, only two circles remain unmarked in red.
还有 七筒的花纹中 没有涂上红色的另两个
One of them represents the suspect,
其中一个指的是嫌疑犯 另一个
while the other the final victim.
指的就是最后的受害者了
You mean the crime is still ongoing?
那么 就是犯罪还会继续了？
Yes. I'm afraid so.
嗯 恐怕是的
If it were meant to represent eight people, wouldn't it be better to leave 8-pin tiles?
但是 如果要表示8个人的话 放个八筒不是更好吗
There's more to the 1 and 7-pin tiles.
一筒和七筒还有另一个意思
The suspect was waiting for those two tiles in order to claim victory.
也就是说 嫌疑犯用这两个牌 一七筒听牌了
And with those, the suspect could have made a quick comeback!
那也是能瞬间逆转牌局的 超厉害的一手啊
I see!
原来如此
Although, another player still won with a cheap hand!
尽管如此还是被某个贱手翻盘了
And that's when the suspect went crazy, right?
所以嫌疑犯愤怒了
Exactly! I'm afraid the other players also felt it unfair,
就是那样 恐怕其他人也一起打了这种受气麻将吧
yet the suspect took it the hardest among them all.
而这对嫌疑犯来说再也无法忍受
And that's the motive.
这就是犯罪动机了
Excuse me...
请问…
How do you explain the alphabet letters, then?
那么 拉丁字母的意思呢
And why did the suspect move the victims to another place to proceed with kill?
为什么还特意搬到别的地方杀害呢
Also...
还有…
What does Ryuuzaki-san's dying message mean?
龙崎先生的死亡讯息是怎么回事
Um...About that...
那…那个…
Well...
那个是…
As for that... Well...We will see in due course.
那个是… 那个…什么什么吧
Superintendent.
管理官
Do the six crime scenes mean anything special to the suspect?
对于嫌疑犯来说 那六个犯罪现场有什么特别的意义吗
If they do,
如果有的话
that's the part which will lead us right to our suspect.
那这个意义与嫌疑犯线索有关的可能性就很大
As for the six victims, they were bound
还有那六个被害者 这六人
to be related to the suspect somehow.
肯定与嫌疑犯有某种联系
Finding out what they had in common should be the key to cracking the case.
找出这六人的共通之处就是查明嫌疑犯的最佳捷径
It's still possible that the connection lies in a game of mahjong, as Mouri-kun said.
毛利老弟所说的是麻将的可能性确实有
Besides, the alphabet letters and black lines on the back of the tiles, as well as
并且 麻将牌背后的拉丁字母和纵线的意思
the dying message "Tanabata...Kyo," should also be taken into account.
“七夕…京…”的死亡讯息的意思 也要考虑
Listen up, everyone. It's highly possible that our suspect will commit another crime.
听好了各位 嫌疑犯在这之后再次犯案的可能性很大
We must stop him no matter what it takes!
即便是赌上警察的威信 也必须要阻止他
At times like this, we must put aside our territorial imperatives and rivalries,
在这样的时刻 要丢弃无谓的势力纷争意识和功名心
and share with each other all the information in order
公开并共享手上所有的信息
to capture our suspect as soon as possible! Do your best in your investigations!
应该尽快地逮捕这个连续杀人犯 给我进行彻底搜查
Yes, sir!
是
Bathroom! Bathroom! Can't hold it!
厕所厕所 不行了
Looks like the meeting is over.
他们好像开完会了吧
Looks like it.
好像是的
Superintendent Matsumoto!
啊 松本警视
Long time no see! How's Sayuri-sensei doing?
好久不见 小百合老师还好吗
Oh, you are Mouri's... My daughter is doing fine.
啊 你是毛利的… 我女儿还是老样子
Well, Mouri. I'm counting on you.
那么毛利 期待你的表现咯
Your humble servant, Kogoro Mouri,
是 鄙人毛利小五郎
vows to do his best and meet your expectations!
必将诚心诚意全力破案以回应您的期待
Okay.
嗯
Thank you for your trust!
您辛苦了
Ah, Detective Chiba, did you lose weight?
啊呀 千叶刑警 你是不是瘦了点啦
You noticed?
被你看出来啦
I'm on a diet now. It's popular on that morning TV program, you know?
最近我在减肥呢 就是现在晨间电视上很流行的那个
Speaking of that,
说到这个
Shiratori, you've put on weight, haven't you?
白鸟 你反而发胖了呢
A-Are you kidding, Mouri-san? I work out twice a week.
别…别开玩笑了毛利先生 我可是一周去健身两次呢
How unusual! You drink black coffee?
真少见呐 你居然喝清咖
Yes.
是啊
The doctor asked me to pay attention to my sugar intake.
最近医生嘱咐说要限制糖分
But if I remember right, you hate sweet food, don't you?
倒是你 不是讨厌甜食吗
Three murder cases happened in a row.
凶杀案已经接连发生3起了
I can't function without glucose!
不摄取点糖分的话不行啦
Well, Inspector Yokomizo...
那个 横沟警部
Huh?
啊？
Yes?
嗯？
Oh, I mean the elder one.
啊 不是 是叫哥哥
Oh.
哦
Say... Is that the boy
那个…那个小孩
you've been talking about, Conan Edogawa-kun?
就是刚才你们说的江户川柯南吗
Oh.
啊
Because he's influenced by Mouri-san's deductions,
也许是因为一直在听毛利先生的推理
he'd sometimes say things that turn out to be quite enlightening.
所以有时也会给出令人吃惊的暗示哦
And he often notices little interesting things-
而且 总是会注意到一些有意思的事情
the things even we pros may overlook...
连我们这些职业警察都会看漏的…
Is that so?
是这样的啊
♪ Oh, crow ♪
♫～乌鸦啊～
♪ Why are you crying ♪
♫～为何要鸣叫～
♪ 'Cause in the mountain, the crow... ♪
♫～乌鸦在山中…～
Detective Yamamura, that song...
山村刑警 那首歌…
I see you may not know that I am...
你还没听说大概不知道吧
Why were you just singing that song, Inspector Yamamura?
为什么唱刚才那首歌呢 山村警部
Why? I just heard it outside the bathroom.
为什么呢 刚才听到洗手间外面传来的
It sounded like someone dialing a phone number.
噼噼啪啪的声音哦
When I left the bathroom...
从洗手间出来的时候
I saw an officer with glasses dialing on his cellphone and...
有个戴眼镜的刑警在打手机呢 咦
Wait, Conan-kun...!
等等柯南
Could it be...
难道
Could it be those guys...
难道那些家伙…
There!
找到了
Hey, Conan-kun!
喂 柯南
Is everything okay?
你怎么了
Shoot!
可恶
Going to the bathroom!
我去下厕所
Conan-kun?
柯南
The bathroom is right here.
厕所不就在这里吗
That was a Porsche 356A. Gin's car!
刚才那个是保时捷356A Gin的爱车
How? How did they get in the meeting?
怎么会 那些家伙怎么会在搜查会议…
What will they do next?
他们到底有什么目的
What did you say?
你说什么
They infiltrated the police meeting?
他们潜入了搜查会议？
Shh! Lower your voice!
嘘 声音太大啦
I hope Haibara didn't hear that.
灰原 没关系的吧
Oh, I think she's in the lab downstairs.
啊 她应该在地下实验室
I'm afraid the disguised officer was Vermouth.
恐怕化装成刑警的是Vermouth
She must have mailed her boss about the meeting while waiting for the elevator.
她应该是在等电梯的时候 将会议结果发给BOSS吧
I see. That's why Detective Yamamura overheard
原来如此 所以山村刑警听到了那个
the number being dialed that sounded like Seven Children.
听起来像「七子之歌」的邮箱地址的按键音
But why...
但是为什么…
Oh, well...
真是的
I was wondering what you guys were whispering about.
我还想你们俩偷偷摸摸地干什么呢
Haibara!
灰原
So, why do you think that was Vermouth?
那么 为什么你认为那是Vermouth呢
The dialed numbers alone wouldn't...
单单靠按键音的话…
Because I also saw Gin's Porsche.
因为Gin的保时捷在那儿
The risk would be too high for them to infiltrate the police without a disguise.
那些家伙不化装就混入警察中的话风险太大
And Vermouth is best at disguising herself.
变装的话Vermouth的可能性是最高的
Anyway, it's safe to assume that the Black Organization
总之 可以确定的是 这次一连串的事件
has something to do with these cases.
肯定以某种形式同那些黑衣人有关
So, I'd like to investigate these cases. Think you can lend me a hand?
所以 我也想调查这些事件 你能帮忙吗
I certainly can...
我是无所谓…
You wouldn't stop anyway, even if I asked you to.
即使我说让你停手 你也不会停的吧
However, you've got to be careful. You should know
但是 一定要慎重 我想你应该知道的
that if they find out who you really are...
如果你的真实身份被那些家伙察觉的话…
Yeah. I know.
嗯 我明白
Eh? They didn't play mahjong?
诶 他们不打麻将？
Yes. According to our investigation, none of the six victims played mahjong.
是的 探听到的结果是 这6个受害者都不打麻将
Sorry, but looks like your deduction was wrong.
真可惜 看来你的推理好像错了啊
We are completely stuck.
完全无计可施啊
If only Kudo-kun were here at a time like this...
这个时候 如果工藤老弟在的话…
By Kudo-kun you mean the high school detective Shinichi Kudo-kun
你说的工藤 就是那个一直协助搜查破案的
who often helps with your cases?
高中生侦探工藤新一吗
Well, yes.
嗯 是的
Now that you mention it, I haven't heard anything about him recently.
说来最近好像没听到他什么消息呢
I bet he's already tired of playing detective.
反正肯定是厌倦了侦探游戏了吧
Ah, no, it's not true.
啊 不 没那回事
He just solved a case at a Taitan High School festival
之前 还在帝丹高中的学园祭上
a short while ago.
破了个案子呢
Takagi-kun!
高木老弟
Sorry! I slipped...
啊 对不起 不小心就…
What's that about?
怎么回事
As per his request, we've been withholding information regarding his involvement.
出于他本人的意愿 我们隐瞒了他参与案件调查一事
I see.
原来如此
He's quite low-key, huh?
真是个低调的人啊
He's changed, for some reason.
最近怎么变这样了啊
He used to be
以前总是比别人
quite the show-off.
更爱出风头的
Taking two days off from school didn't cause any problems for you, right?
向学校请两天假好像没什么收获吧
Um... I guess.
呃… 是吧
And
是啊
what about the correlation between the mahjong titles and the alphabet letters?
那个麻将牌和拉丁字母的意思呢
I still don't know.
那个也还不知道
Nor do I know the meaning of "Tanabata...Kyo."
“七夕…京…”的意思也还…
Wow! Mitsuhiko-kun, it's amazing!
好厉害啊光彦 真强
It's a rhinoceros beetle, isn't it?
那个 是独角仙吧
Yeah. I'm pretty good at it!
是的 这个我可是相当拿手哦
But some people do mean things like putting tape on beetles.
但别做过分的事啊 在人家翅膀上贴标签什么的
You mean Orihime-san, right? I wonder who did it.
啊 像上次那个织女一样 那种事情到底是谁做的呢
Me, too.
就是呀
Say, Genta-kun, is that a snake you made?
话说回来 元太 你做的是蛇吗
Can't you tell? It's an eel! Eel!
这都看不出来啊 是鳗鱼啦 鳗～鱼～
Oh, an eel again?
唉 还是鳗鱼啊
Genta-kun, you really love eels, don't you?
元太 真是很喜欢鳗鱼呢
You even wrote it on your Tanabata wish card.
上次七夕装饰的诗笺上不是也写着的吗
"I want to have a big bowl of Unadon. Genta."
想吃鳗鱼饭吃的饱饱的 元太
Come to think of it, Tanabata is tomorrow.
这么说起来 明天就是七夕了呢
Tanabata...Kyo...
七夕…京…
What's that supposed to mean?
到底指什么呢
Come on! You should turn that off during a meeting!
真是的 开会中要关机
Yes?
抱歉
It's me.
是我
And?
然后呢？
What?
什么
Oh! Roger that!
啊 好的
Good news!
好消息
I was told that a man suspected to be our serial killer might show up in Beika City.
连续杀人案的嫌疑男子也许会在米花市现身
Are you sure?
你说什么
Minoru Fukase, 27 years old.
深濑稔 27岁
One year ago, he stabbed
在碓冰岭被杀的阵野修平
Shuuhei Jinno-san to death on Usui pass.
就是一年前被其用刀刺死
He was also badly wounded, and remains on our wanted list.
而他本人身负重伤 现正在通缉中
I asked our men to monitor his girlfriend,
我们让手下监视了他的女朋友
who, based on my intel, boarded a train from Nagano to Tokyo,
并且收到消息说她坐车从长野到东京
and just arrived at Beika Station.
已经在米花站下车了
Risa Yoshii, 21 years old.
吉井理沙 21岁
She works at a bar in Nagano.
在长野市内的酒吧工作
So, why did this Fukase guy kill Jinno-san?
那么 这个叫深濑的男子刺杀阵野先生的动机是？
While they were lining up at the Tropical Land amusement park,
好像是在多罗碧加乐园排队的时候
Jinno-san warned him not to smoke, which got him fired up.
阵野先生警告他不能抽烟 他就怀恨在心了
Tropical Land...
多罗碧加乐园…
Takagi-kun?
高木
What came to mind just now?
你想到什么了吗
Could it be...
该不会…
Could it be that all the victims were all waiting in the same line?
该不会 被害者全部都是当时排在同一队列的人吧
What? Explain, please.
什么 你详细说明一下
Yes.
是
There are two variations of the mahjong tiles found near the victims.
放在被害者身旁的麻将牌有两种
Jinno-san's was 1-pin,
阵野先生的
and the others' were 7-pins.
一筒 和其他人的七筒
And, if we place them into the circles as indicated by the red marks...
把各个麻将牌的红圆的地方这样排的话…
the victims may have lined up this way, right?
被害者是以这样的顺序排队的
I see.
原来如此
Then, that Fukase...
那 深濑…
Alright. Megure, get your men and go along with Inspector Yamato.
好 目暮 带上手下和大和警部同行
Gosh, I can't believe they sent you!
受不了 为什么连你都跟来了
For once, I wanted to ride on the capital highway!
我想去首都至高点跑跑看嘛
Inspector Yamato, what about you?
大和警部您呢？
Now, let's spread out as planned.
好 就按照事先说的那样分头埋伏
She's the suspect?
嫌疑犯吗
Or, could she be...
还是那个人…
Minoru!
阿稔
We've got eyes on Fukase.
深濑出现了
Hold this position.
各自原地待命
Do not get spotted.
可别被发现了哦
Hurry! Hurry!
快 快
The game shop's on the 7th floor, right?
游戏房 是在七楼吧
Yep. Let's get some ice cream after.
嗯 回去的时候去吃冰淇淋吧
I'm gonna get a vanilla and chocolate double scoop!
我要香草和巧克力双层的
Inspector, we have children around Fukase!
警部 深濑旁边有小孩子
Remain calm. Make our move after the children are gone.
镇静 等小孩子们离开深濑后再行动
Roger.
明白
-Which floor is this? -One more to go.
这是几楼 还有一楼吧
Suspect has arrived on the 5th floor.
通过五楼
We are almost there!
到七楼了
Now, move in!
好 行动
Roger that!
明白
Wait...
等等…
That idiot!
那个笨蛋
Fukase! Freeze! Police!
深濑 不许动 警察
You have nowhere to run!
你已经无路可逃了
Damn!
靠
Stop it, Fukase!
你别乱来
Stay away! Or I'll kill her!
不许过来 敢过来我就弄死她
Damn!
该死
Don't move! I'll stab her if you dare!
不许动 敢乱动别怪刀子不长眼
Stop! You can't get away with it!
住手 你跑得了和尚跑不了庙
Shut up! Stay away!
废什么话 谁让你过来的
Stay away!
不准过来
Get out of my way!
都给我滚开
Okay! Just calm down!
好 好 你冷静点
What a waste of time!
居然敢耽误我的工夫
He passed out. What happened?
好像晕过去了 怎么回事
Stay away from him!
离他远点儿
Calm down, Risa-san. Drop the knife.
别冲动 理沙小姐 放下刀子
No.
我不
That won't change anything. Drop it.
你这样也无济于事的 扔掉刀子
I won't! Stay away from him!
不要 不要 放开他
Alright, that's enough, Risa-san.
好 这就好 理沙小姐
You don't want to commit another crime.
你没必要再给自己增添罪名
I'm sorry!
对不起
Are you okay, Inspector?
您没事吧 警部
Don't worry. My belly fat has some thickness to it.
用不着担心 我肚子上的脂肪厚着呢
I'm sorry!
十分抱歉
I'm so sorry. I dropped my guard.
真对不起 是我放松了警惕
It's okay. I can't let another prefecture's officer get hurt in my jurisdiction, can I?
没事 在我们的管辖区怎能让别处的同事受伤呢
What's wrong?
怎么了
Well...Where's that female hostage?
没…那个被当人质的女人呢
You are just gonna walk away like this?
就打算就这样走人了吗
Isn't there something you want from that guy?
你同那男的不是还得唱一段儿吗
Vermouth.
Vermouth
I didn't have any other choice. You pushed me into a corner.
我也没办法啊 还不是你逼我这么做的
Besides, perhaps that man isn't the killer.
而且 那男的可能不是凶手
Yeah. That's true.
是 没错
Take it easy! My right shoulder hurts!
轻点儿 右肩疼着呢
Your right shoulder hurts?
右肩疼？
Wait a sec, just now...
对了你刚才…
Stay away!
不准过来
A man who can't even raise his right arm can't be our assailant.
抬不起右臂的人 不可能舞刀弄枪
Assuming he didn't hurt it after committing the crime, that is.
只要不是行凶后才疼的
So, you recognized me after all.
你还是认出我了啊
Your ankle.
你的脚
My ankle?
脚？
There was a bulge near your right ankle.
右脚踝胀鼓鼓的
You have a gun concealed there, no?
藏了把枪在那儿吧
And, the guy wounded your left cheek with a knife, but you didn't even bleed.
还有 你左脸被他划了一刀 却滴血未见
Jeez...
真是的…
I guess I'll have to make a blood-seeping mask next time.
看来下次要换个能流血的面具呢
I think
我估计你是
you purposely made yourself his hostage, and planned to utilize your gun
故意让他绑为人质
to turn the tables on him once you were out of the police's sight.
引开警察后 再开枪来个绝地反击
What a well-thought-out plan!
精心布局的计划啊
I doubt you'd really put your gun to use, anyway.
不过 如果是你的话都不需要开枪的吧
I didn't expect to receive a compliment from you.
没想到还能受到你的表扬啊
Why is your Organization involved in this serial murder case?
你们组织为何要插手这次的杀人案
How straightforward of you!
挺直截了当嘛
Spit it out.
快说
NOC.
（Non Official Cover：伪装成普通人潜入其他国家进行活动的 密谍报人员、没有外交身份掩护的情报人员，俗称间谍。）
A member of yours working undercover as a civilian became one of the victims?
在那些受害人当中有扮成普通百姓的组织成员？
Right. That agent, perhaps for the sake of safety,
没错 那个间谍可能出于保险起见
carried a memory card containing our entire NOC list.
把装有组织的间谍名单的记忆卡带在身上
The organization had planned to get rid of him.
组织近期应该会干掉他
But who would've thought...
可就在这节骨眼上…
That he would be killed by someone else first.
他先让人给杀了
Correct. And then the killer took the memory card. Most likely without knowing its value.
对 之后凶手拿走了记忆卡 我估计他也不知道这是什么
I see. It would be trouble for you
原来如此 让警察逮住凶手
should the police catch the killer and get the memory card, so...
数据一旦被看到就麻烦了 于是…
Wait, the fact that you are here means a NOC has been planted in the police!
你能来这里就说明搜查组人员中有内鬼
No. You had one of your partners disguise as an officer.
不对 是你安插同党化装成搜查人员的
That's why you infiltrated the meeting, right?
所以你才会混进搜查会议
You wanted to ensure that your partner's disguise was still airtight.
就为了确认你的人伪装得是否顺利
Otherwise, you would've stayed undercover yourself.
要不然就是你潜伏下去了
Who is it? Who is he disguised as? Is the real officer in danger?
是谁 装成了谁 真正的搜查人员有危险吗
The time for sharing tips is over. You're on your own for the rest.
我呢就点到为止 接着就该你自己去查了
His codename is Irish.
代号是Irish
Irish...
Irish…
Yep. Irish whiskey is nicely distilled, with a mild taste.
对 一种杂味较少 很温和的威士忌
Excuse me, security guard.
那个 保安大哥
This kid is lost.
这个孩子好像迷路了
Lost?
迷路了？
No...
不…
Good luck! I wish you all the best!
Good Luck！祝你好运哦
Damn!
可恶
Yes? It's Megure. Oh, Superintendent.
是 我是目暮 是管理官啊
We just got a call from a painter named Sumire Shindo
刚才接到一个叫新堂堇的画家的电话
saying she has a clue that may lead to our suspect.
据称有连续杀人案的线索
The address is in Hachioji City.
地址在八王子市
Yes, sir! Got it.
是 是 我知道了
Sato! Takagi!
佐藤 高木
Head to Hachioji now!
马上去八王子
Yes, sir!
是
Got it. Sumire Shindo, right?
我知道了 叫新堂堇吧
Not good, Boss. If we go from here,
不好办啊大哥 从这里出发的话
even if we are ahead of the cops, we'll still get caught before we get the job done.
就算比条子先到 下手前准会撞见
We won't be running into the cops.
不会见着条子的
It's me.
是我
Nice! We made it in time!
很好 终于赶上了
I'll take right.
我 右边
Okay. Leave the left to me.
OK 老娘左边
Cute boy...
一个郎才…
Pretty lady...
一个女貌…
What's going on?
怎么回事
Stay calm! Slowly pull over!
冷静点 慢点开到路边
It's hot! We got a flat tire!
好烫 果然爆胎了
And another here.
这边也是
Takagi-kun, contact Shiratori-kun.
高木 你联系白鸟
Got it.
是
Damn.
妈的
Someone got here first.
慢了一步
We can't stay for long.
此地不宜久留
Let's go.
收兵
What? No one's there?
什么？人不在？
Are you sure she's not just left home?
应该不会是外出了吧
I'm sure. The room has been trashed.
是的 室内有打斗过的痕迹
I'm sure the suspect abducted Shindo-san and fled.
可以断定是嫌疑犯开车把新堂带走了
Requesting backup A.S.A.P.
紧急通缉
Please call for the forensics team.
麻烦叫鉴识科来
Roger.
好的
Thanks.
再见
Takagi-kun...
高木
What is it?
怎么？
Sato-san?
佐藤小姐？
Disguised as an officer?
装成了搜查人员？
Yeah. The codename is Irish. Ever heard of it?
嗯 代号是Irish 听过没
No. Never.
没有 没听说过
I see.
这样啊
If only I had a clue about who this guy is...
哪怕知道是什么样的人 装成了谁也好啊…
I think you should leave it.
我劝你别插手
If it's true that this Irish was disguised as an officer,
如果Irish乔装成搜查人员
he must have noticed that you ran after Vermouth after the meeting.
绝对会怀疑会议后觉察到Vermouth而飞奔出去的你
Yeah...but...
是啊 可是…
Don't you get it?
你还不懂吗
The more cases you solve, the more obvious it will be that you are Shinichi Kudo!
你破的案件越多 就越证明你是工藤新一啊
Ai-kun...
小哀…
I know what you are worried about.
我知道你的担心
But I can't just leave it be. It concerns the life of the officer Irish disguised himself as.
可是不破不行 被Irish乔装的人生死未卜
Anyway, there's no doubt that Irish already infiltrated that police meeting.
总之 Irish就混在参加会议的搜查人员当中
I need to find out who he is by any means necessary,
在想办法搞清那人身份的同时
and catch the culprit before they do
还要抢在他们前头抓到凶手
in order to get the memory card that NOC was carrying.
再把被内鬼拿走的记忆卡搞到手
That memory card could be the key to taking them down once and for all.
就这么一张卡或许能一举击溃他们
But can you trust what Vermouth said?
可是真的信得过吗 Vermouth的话
She was already aware that Haibara is Sherry.
她老早就知道灰原是Sherry
She may even know my identity as well.
可能也知道我的身份
But, for whatever reason, she's kept it from the Organization.
可她却没向组织报告
I have no choice but to trust her for now.
当前唯有相信她
Even so, she still called you out to the shrine like she was leery of you.
意外的是 还提防着把你叫到神社去
She was leery of Irish.
她在提防着Irish
Let's not meet except for at school until everything's settled.
事情摆平之前 咱俩除在学校外还是别见面为好
Only as a precaution.
毕竟要以防万一
What's up, Gin?
你找我什么事 Gin
Where have you been for the past two hours?
这两个钟头 你到哪儿去了
Seems you've been places where you had to turn your cell off.
好像是在必须关闭手机的地方吧
What are you getting at?
你在怀疑我？
Forget it.
也罢
Just focus on finishing your job.
你只管专心完成给你的任务
By the way, the one who used the drug to poison the high school detective was you, right?
对了 用药物处理掉那个高中生侦探的是你吧
Who are you talking about?
你在说哪件事
Shinichi Kudo...
工藤新一…
Remember?
你忘了吗
What happened?
怎么了啊
Sorry!
不好意思
I broke your bowl!
打碎你的碗了
It's okay.
没事啦
But you seldom break things, though.
很少见到你打碎餐具呢
Yeah. What's with me today?
是啊 我这是怎么了
Apparently the victim is Sumire Shindo.
可以确定遇害人是新堂堇
Okay. Got it. 3:00, right?
好的 我知道了 3点是吧
See you then.
那回头再说
Was that Detective Takagi?
高木刑警打来的吗
There's another meeting at 3:00.
3点又有搜查会议
Any progress on the case?
有进展吗
Sumire Shindo's body was found.
据说发现了新堂堇的尸体
Where?
地点呢
He said it was in Kanagawa Prefecture's Ayase City.
说是神奈川县绫濑市
Was there another 7-pin mahjong tile?
那麻将的七筒呢
Yeah. The red mark this time is on the top-right of the four bottom circles.
红圈圈是下面四个圆的右上角
But instead of a letter on the back, there's a triangle.
背面不是字母 而是三角…
Hey! Go to school!
老实点上学去
It's true!
真是的
Really strange!
好奇怪啊
Morning!
早啊
Conan-kun!
柯南
It's bad! Your dolphin's fin is missing!
不好啦 海豚的背鳍不见了
The fin?
背鳍？
Oh. It's true!
啊 真的呢
There are marks of a leather glove!
这是皮手套的痕迹
A mysterious case has occurred!
发生谜案了呢
That's an exaggeration. I bet it was knocked off by accident when someone was cleaning.
太夸张了 估计是谁打扫的时候碰掉了吧
But we searched everywhere and couldn't find it.
都找过了啊 没找着
It's okay. I'll just make another one and put it on.
算啦 再做一个装上去
Do you think that fin...
莫非那背鳍…
No way. Don't worry.
不可能的 别担心
It must be those people...
肯定是那伙人
Just looking from here gives me the chills. We really lucked out!
这么看来 还好没出大的事故 冒我一身冷汗
Don't you think it's strange?
你不觉得奇怪吗
There's no way that two tires would burst at the same time.
不可能两个轮子同时爆胎的
Maybe there were nails on the road.
是不是路上有钉子啊
A sniper...
有狙击
Our tires must have been shot flat by someone from this bridge.
有人从天桥上狙击了轮胎
I saw a car parked here.
那里好像停着车
Really?
不会吧
Takagi-kun, it might be just a wild hunch, but I think there might be another
高木 也许是突发奇想 这次的案件先不说凶手
group of people lurking around in this case besides our suspect.
我觉得有一伙来路不明的人在暗中涌动
Lurking around?
来路不明的？
At Shindo-san's studio, her paint tube was stepped on twice.
新堂先生的画室里的颜料被踩过两次
The first time, it caused paint to squirt out.
颜料管被踩到 颜料被压出
After the paint had dried, someone stepped on it again.
而滑出的颜料干后又被踩了一脚
It means after the culprit abducted Shindo-san, someone else visited the scene.
这说明凶手带走新堂先生后 还有人来过
Really? Maybe the culprit left after the paint had dried.
是吗 也许凶手是等到颜料干后再走的吧
Moreover, the female hostage who disappeared at the mall in Beika City was also suspicious.
另一点 从米花镇的商场里消失的女人也颇可疑
Could she have been a partner of those people,
难不成她也是那伙人的同党
merely playing the part of a hostage?
故意当人质的吧
Come on, you're thinking too much!
她这又何必呢 你多虑了吧
You're right. I guess I think too much.
是啊 是多虑了吧
But if it's true,
但是 如果事实如此
there's got to be one of them in the cops too,
那警察内部就有内鬼在里应外合
and the spy would have been among the meeting attendees.
而且就在参加会议的成员当中
The dark knight helmet?
黑衣骑士的头盔？
It's damaged. People in the drama club are arguing about it.
给弄坏了 刚才戏剧社那些人吵起来了
The bowl...
饭碗…
I broke Conan-kun's bowl last night.
昨晚我打碎了柯南的碗
And now, the helmet Shinichi wore is damaged.
然后这回是新一戴过的头盔
I have a bad feeling about this.
有种不祥之感
Aren't you thinking too much?
是不是敏感过头了啊
That kid and Shinichi-kun aren't related in any way.
那个小鬼头和新一 八竿子打不着的
Even so...I need to tell him about it.
话虽如此…还是先告诉他吧
The dark knight helmet is damaged?
黑衣骑士的头盔坏了？
Oh, no! My fingerprints
坏事了 那头盔上
were on that helmet!
有我的指纹
Damn! If both the dolphin fin and the helmet were their doing...
可恶 如果海豚背鳍和头盔都是他们干的
What do I do now? If I can't figure out a solution,
该怎么办 要是不赶快想个对策的话
Ran and Mr. Mouri and everybody around me will be in danger.
会连累小兰和大叔他们的
The memory card! I'll have the upper hand if I can get the memory card!
记忆卡 只要将卡拿到手就能夺取先机
I have to hurry and catch the culprit!
尽早抓获凶手
I bet it's from Shinichi-kun.
新一发来的？
Yes.
嗯
He says, "I'm dealing with a tough case right now,"
说是在处理一件棘手的案件
"so don't call or text me."
让我别发邮件 别打电话给他
But...
可是…
What tough case?
什么样的棘手案件啊
At least let me hear your voice, Shinichi...
好歹让我听听你的声音嘛 新一
That should do it.
这下好了
What gets me is the message "Tanabata...Kyo."
可疑的是“七夕…京…”这句话
What does that mean?
到底有什么来头？
Tanabata...Kyo... Kyoto?
七夕…京… 京都？
Oh, Kudo. It's been a while.
工藤 有些日子没联系啦
What is it that you wanted to ask me about?
有什么事问我啊
I see.
原来如此
Who are you talking to?
跟谁打电话呢
You scared me, moron!
吓死我了 笨蛋
I'm sorry!
抱歉 抱歉
You scared the hell out of me!
差点被你害死
So, you are talking to someone important, aren't you?
原来你在跟那么重要的大人物煲电话啊
Don't be silly! It's Kudo!
笨蛋 是工藤啦
Regarding that serial murder case...
他问我连续杀人案调查中
He asked me whether "Tanabata Kyoto" rings a bell or not.
“七夕 京都”能不能联想到什么的
Sorry about that, Kudo.
不好意思啊 工藤
That stupid Kazuha just interrupted me.
和叶那个笨蛋又管闲事来了
Speaking of "Tanabata Kyoto"
要说“七夕 京都”嘛
Doesn't he mean the Mitarashi Festival?
是说御净手庙会吧
The one held in Kitano Tenman Temple.
在北野天满宫那个
Also, the Tanabata Festival in Jishu-Jinja Shrine is famous, too!
还有地主神社的七夕祭典也蛮有名的
Why don't we go there tonight?
对啦 今晚一起去吧
Go by yourself! Did you hear that, Kudo?
你想去就自己去吧 听到了没 工藤
Yeah. But I don't see the connection.
可一时半会儿也想不出联系
Me neither. Other things that come to mind are...
也许吧 要说其它的线索呢
Come on! Let's go! We don't have to spend the night if we go to Kyoto. It's just a one-day trip.
去嘛 去京都不用住酒店 能当天来回的
I wouldn't stay in a hotel anyway, idiot!
你傻啊 你不说我也不住酒店的
There was a fire there two years ago, remember?
前年的大火你忘了吗
Stingy!
小气鬼
Hey, Hattori...
服部
What was that fire about?
大火是怎么回事
There was a fire in Kyoto the year before last.
前年京都起大火了
Come to think of it, it was on the night of Tanabata.
好像就是七夕那晚
Tell me more.
说详细点
I remember the hotel was named Vega.
好像酒店名叫“织女星”
Two guests died in the fire.
有两个客人死在里面
Hattori, please get more information about the fire for me. It's an emergency!
服部 这场火灾你再去详细调查一下 很急
Okay.
好咧
Wait, Heiji! What are you doing?
喂 平次 你干嘛啊
Class is starting soon!
要上课啦
Just tell the teacher
你就跟老师说
that Hattori-kun went to Vega to meet Orihime-san!
服部七夕上织女星找织女去了
Hey! Who's Orihime-san?
喂 织女是谁
Fire... Do the red marks and letters on the tiles represent a fire?
起火…麻将上的红色记号和字母指的是火灾吗
The cause was a lit cigarette that belonged to a guest on the fifth floor. The emergency staircase was unusable.
起火原因是五楼的房客抽烟不慎 导致逃生楼梯不能使用
Another guest on the sixth floor died from smoke inhalation.
另外六楼的一个房客 被浓烟呛死
Nanako Honjue, from Mitaka City, Jindai Ward.
本上奈奈子 三鹰市神代人
Mizutani-san!
水谷先生
Mizutani-kun is out.
水谷他出去了
Do you know where he went?
你知道上哪儿去了吗
So, you are Detective Mouri's assistant?
原来你是毛利侦探的助手啊
My name is Shun Sawamura. I'm a law student at Jounan University.
我叫泽村俊 在上南大法学系读研 要多多指教哦
Thank you! Please don't tell anyone about this.
谢谢你 这事儿跟谁都不能说哦
It's a confidential investigation.
我们在绝密调查呢
That's why he sent a kid like you?
所以才派你这样的小孩子啊
So, Kosuke Mizutani-san and Nanako Honjue-san were...
那么 水谷浩介先生和本上奈奈子小姐是…
Lovers. They ran away from Chiba to here together because their families disapproved of their relationship.
恋人关系啊 不过家长坚决反对 好像是从千叶私奔来的
Ran away...
私奔…
On the day of Tanabata two years ago, they took a trip to Kyoto and stayed at that business hotel.
前年七夕节 两个人来京都旅游 就住在那家商务酒店里
And then he went to visit a friend in the city by himself.
可是呢 他独自去见了个家住京都的朋友
The hotel caught fire during that time.
就在那段时间里 酒店让大火给烧了
"If only I hadn't gone out by myself, Nana wouldn't have died."
“要是自己不去见朋友 奈奈也不会死”
He began crying after saying that.
他一把鼻涕一把泪地说啊
What does Mizutani-san do for work?
水谷先生有工作吗
He was working a part-time job, but he stopped working after his girlfriend died.
原来还打打零工 自从女朋友死后基本上没干活
He hasn't been here for a long time.
好些日子也没回这儿了
Where does he live now?
那水谷先生现在在哪儿呢
Who knows? Oh, maybe in Chiba.
难说… 哦 可能在千叶吧
Today's the second anniversary of his girlfriend's death.
今天是他女友的2周年忌辰
Then he went to a temple?
那 是去了庙里？
Maybe. You might have better luck asking her big brother.
也许吧 你问问她哥就知道了
Hold on a second.
你等等哦
Prior to her death, her big brother came here several times.
她死之前 她哥来过好几次
He told me to contact him if his sister was in any trouble.
说妹妹要是有什么困难就找他
Found it! Look.
找到了 你看
It's her brother's card. And this is Mizutani-kun.
她哥的名片 还有 这是水谷
May I take a note of this number?
电话号码能记一下吗
Sure.
可以
And, please give me your cellphone number, too, Sawamura-san.
还有 泽村先生你的手机号码也告诉我吧
Hello? Hattori.
喂 服部吗
Hey, Kudo! Big news!
工藤 头彩啊 中头彩啦
The names of the seven victims you sent
你发来的七个遇害人的姓名
match the names of the guests on the sixth floor during the fire.
和火灾时住在六楼的客人的名字是一致的
There were two more guests on the sixth floor.
住六楼的还有两个
Nanako Honjue-san and Kosuke Mizutani-san.
本上奈奈子小姐和水谷浩介先生
You knew already? Then, how about this?
你都知道了嘛 那这条如何
That Mizutani guy also came here and asked about the same thing one year ago.
这个水谷呢 一年前和我一样来调查过此事
I bet this case has everything to do with the fire two years ago.
这次的案子铁定跟两年前的火灾有牵连
But what is it all about? If Mizutani is the culprit, what is his motive?
可是怎么回事呢 假设水谷是凶手 那动机何在？
Wasn't Honjue-san's death an accident?
本上小姐是死于事故吧
Hattori,
服部
how many elevators are there in the hotel?
那酒店有几台电梯
Elevators? There's only one, I think.
电梯？一台吧
What's the capacity?
能容纳几人
Hold on.
你稍等
Seven people.
电梯容纳人数是7人
Why are you asking, Kudo?
这有什么关系吗 工藤
I'll get out! I'll get out!
我下 我下
I see! I get it, Kudo!
原来如此 我懂啦 工藤
I guess on the day of the fire Nanako Honjue-san was...
我估计起火那天 本上奈奈子小姐
Pushed out of the elevator after boarding it.
是被赶出了电梯
Because the eighth person wanted to get in forced her out.
被第八个要进去的人强拉出去的
The eighth person would be the one with the 1-pin tile, Jinno-san.
第八个人就是一筒 阵野先生
The other six would have been standing in the elevator on the positions suggested by the 7-pin's red circles.
其他六个人的站位就是七筒上的圆圈
And the last circle would represent Nanako-san's position.
剩下一个就是奈奈子小姐站的位置
I'm afraid so. The shape of the Mahjong tiles corresponds to the shape of the elevator, with the black lines as the doors.
也许吧 麻将本身就像电梯箱 背面中间的黑线代表门
Exactly!
太对了
When Jinno-san got on, the buzzer went off. That's why he wanted someone out.
最后阵野先生要进去时蜂鸣器响了 就想赶个人出去
And he picked Nanako-san.
他找准了奈奈子小姐
The other six, worrying they'd be forced out as well,
其他六个装作没看见
pretended not to see anything, which in turn encouraged Jinno-san.
都担心自己会被拉出去 很可能反而支持了阵野先生
After missing the ride, Nanako-san died since it was too late for her to escape.
没坐上电梯的奈奈子却逃晚了
So, is there a problem with my deduction?
怎样 我的推理有错吗
No. It's just that I still don't understand what the letters on the tiles mean.
没有 麻将上的字母的意思想不通
Yeah. It is strange that there was a triangle instead of a letter on the seventh tile.
对啊 第七个并非字母而是三角 这点很奇怪
If the last circle really does represent Nanko-san,
剩下的红圆圈如果是指奈奈子小姐
there shouldn't be any more murders.
应该不会再出命案了
Hopefully. Anyway, I'll try to locate Mizutani-san first.
希望如此 总之 先找出水谷先生再说
Thank you, Hattori. Seriously...
谢谢你 服部 说真的…
Kudo.
工藤
You know what? I found an awesome restaurant that serves Okonomiyaki.
对了 我发现一家超好吃的随心烤的店
I'll take you there next time you come over.
下次带你去吃 过来玩啊
Please do. I'll wait for you.
一定要来啊 我在这儿等着你
Yeah, I will. Later.
嗯 好的 先这样
Kudo.
工藤
Please do come!
一定要来啊
What? On July 7th two years ago?
什么 两年前的7月7号？
All the victims were in Kyoto on that day?
遇害人当天全去过京都？
Yes. We've confirmed it through our investigations.
对的 这是走访调查的结果
That means...
也就是说…
the "Tanabata...Kyo" our witness heard
目击者听到了“七夕…京…”
refers to "Tanabata Kyoto."
其实是指“七夕 京都”
I'm having people looking into exactly what happened on that day in Kyoto. But...
我正托人在查那天京都发生了什么事 但问题是…
what do these messages the culprit has left on the mahjong tiles actually mean?
犯人留在麻将上的信息
Only the bottom-left circle hasn't been marked red. He may commit another crime.
七筒左下角还有个红圆 犯人很可能会再干一票
And...
而且…
it's no coincidence that today is July 7th.
今天是7月7号也并非碰巧
So, the last victim will die today?
那最后一个人就是今天？
Where and who, though?
到底会在哪儿杀谁呢
Could it be someone among us...?
莫非就在这些人中间…
I've got it!
我晓得啦
The seven locations represent the shape of a certain animal!
这七处现场表示着某种动物的形状
A certain animal?
动物？
Here, look!
各位看官
If we connect the different crime scenes with lines...
将各个现场这样用线连起来
Do you see it now?
这下能明白了吧
This long line is the neck. And here's the chest. This is the front leg, then the back, and then the hind leg.
这条长线是脖子 这里是胸部、前脚、背 然后是后脚
So, rather than Nessie from Loch Ness,
这不是尼斯湖水怪
It's Assie, from Lake Ashino!
而是芦湖的 芦怪是也
Assie?
芦怪？
Is there even such a thing?
有那种东西吗
Nah, never heard of it.
没有吧 我都没听说过
I don't get it at all!
听得一头雾水啊
Then, how about this?
那 这样看看如何
Well, if you put it this way...
嗯 这样一说的确就…
It does look like one!
看上去是很像芦怪
But, why Assie?
可为什么一定是芦怪呢
It could be Lake Yamanaka's Yassie.
也可以是山中湖的山怪啊
Take a close look at the shape of the lake.
你好好看看湖的形状
Lake Yamanaka is shaped like a whale.
山中湖是条鲸鱼
What about Lake Ashino?
芦湖才是…
I got it, Mouri-san!
我明白了 毛利先生
The next crime scene will be at Assie's nose!
下一个案发现场就是芦怪的鼻尖
You amateur, Inspector Yokomizo! I did it on purpose to trick you. It should be here.
幼稚 横沟警部 我是故意迷惑你的 实际上在这儿
It's in Gunma Prefecture's Annaka City!
目标位置 群马县安中市
I know Annaka City very well.
安中市啊 我可熟悉了
I'll go there, too! You lead the way!
我也去 你带路
Yes!
遵命
I'll go with you!
那我也去
What are you doing?
干什么啊
Don't go!
别去
But how could those two deal with a vicious killer?
可是就凭他们两个人对付凶残的对手…
Two is enough.
两个人足够了
That was fun!
真好玩
Yes! I wish Conan-kun had come!
是啊 要是柯南能来就更好了
Say, don't you think Conan's been weird lately? He went back alone again today.
你们不觉得柯南最近怪怪的吗 今天又自个儿回去了
I bet his cold hasn't gone away yet.
肯定是感冒还没好
He even took two days off from school.
还请了两天假
The bus is here.
车来了
It's a rhinoceros beetle!
独角仙
This bus must have come from Beika Forest.
这辆公交车是从米花森林发车的吧
I see. The beetle flew onto that man's shoulder and was taken here by accident.
原来如此 它就粘在进森林里的叔叔的肩膀上 结果被带回来了
Convenience store tape!
是便利店的胶条
Again?
又来了
So there are more beetles suffering from this prank! How sad!
原来还有其他受到恶作剧的虫子啊 好可怜
I can't remove it! It's so sticky!
撕不下来 贴死了
Let's ask the professor to peel it off.
还是让博士帮忙撕吧
And to treat us some snacks!
顺便整点好吃的
Kazuki-san, there's only one anonymous bouquet today.
和树先生 今天只有一束不知道谁送的花了
I know.
是啊
Hello.
你好
You are Detective Mouri's assistant?
你是毛利侦探的助手
Yeah?
真的吗
I'm looking for Mizutani-san as part of an investigation,
我们在调查一起案子 所以要找水谷先生
but it seems that he didn't come to the memorial service, huh?
但是他好像没来参加法事嘛
Oh, he stopped by this early morning and left a bouquet.
哦 他今天一大早来放了束花就走了
Just left a bouquet?
就放了一束花？
My parents still can't forgive him for running away with my sister.
我爸妈至今都没原谅他和妹妹私奔一事
That's why...
然后…
The one she said was left anonymously...
那伯母说的不知道谁送的花
Was that from Mizutani-san?
就是水谷先生送来的
She said it was the only one today. So there were more before?
今天只有一束 也就是说还有其他送来的
Yeah. There were more other than his.
嗯 除他之外的也有
When? And do you know from where?
何时？知道是从哪儿发的吗
Yes. There were four on the day of the funeral two years ago,
知道啊 前年的葬礼那天4束
respectively from Matsumoto, Kawasaki,
松本市和川崎
Numazu and Kamakura.
还有沼津 镰仓
There were three on the memorial service day last year,
去年的一周年忌辰那天3束
respectively from Tokorozawa, Odawara, and Hachioji.
那次是所泽 小田原 八王子
They are the places where the seven victims were from.
这些都是受害人住的地方
Actually, when I met Kousuke-kun this morning,
事实上今早碰到浩介时
he said something strange.
他说了些挺奇怪的话
Something strange?
奇怪的话？
"There are eight people I can't forgive. Now, only one remains."
“不能原谅的人有八个 现在还剩一个”
This was done
这个呢
by the same person. The way he taped the V-shape is the same.
应该是出自同一人之手 胶条的贴法是同样的V字形
I see! It could be someone's message!
对了 也许这是谁留下的信息啊
Message?
信息
Do you know what the message is?
你们知道他要传达些什么吗
The answer is "Help!"
答案就是Help 救命
Why?
为什么呢
This bug is called a "beetle" in English.
独角仙在英语里是Beetle
My Volkswagen has a similar shape so it's also called a Beetle.
我的爱车德国大众 由于其形状相似 所以称为甲壳虫
Also, "beet" in beetle shares the same pronunciation with a musical "beat."
另外 这Beetle跟音乐上的Beat（节拍）一搭配
So, by combining the two you get The Beatles, the legendary band!
得出的名字就是鼎鼎有名的Beatles（甲壳虫乐队）
The Beatles?
Beatles？
Their first album was titled Please Please Me.
他们的第一张专辑名是 Please Please Me
The second, With the Beatles.
第二张 With The Beatles
The third, A Hard Day's Night.
第三张 A Hard Day's Night
The fourth, Beatles for Sale.
第四张 Beatles For Sale
And the fifth, Help!
然后第五张 Help!
So, do you get it?
怎么样 弄懂了没
What's "Beatles"?
Beatles是什么啊
A foreign band.
好像是外国的乐队
You guys don't know The Beatles?
你们几个不知道甲壳虫乐队啊
Never heard of them! Not at all!
听都没听过～完全不知～鬼才知道～
My sister used to listen to their music a lot.
想起来了 我姐姐常常听的
She loved the oldies.
她很喜欢那些老歌老调的
Oldies...?
老歌老调…
I wish he had treated us to food instead of quizzes!
又是猜谜语 还不如请吃饭呢
Help means someone is asking for assistance, right?
Help是指某人在求助吧
Yes.
对啊
Then the Detective Boys should come to rescue!
轮到咱少年侦探团出马了
I finally understand the meaning of "Tanabata Kyoto."
我终于搞懂“七夕 京都”的含义了
All seven victims checked in?
遇害的七个人住宿过？
The victim of the fire was a young girl named Nanako Honjue.
火灾的遇害人本上奈奈子这年轻女子
And her boyfriend, Kosuke Mizutani, came here to look into the case a year ago.
她男朋友水谷浩介就一年前火灾一事来查过
Also, two hours earlier, Heiji Hattori-kun came and inquired about the same thing.
接着 2个小时前服部平次也来过问同起案件
Yeah, that's right. I'm interested in this case.
对啊 我对这案子颇有兴趣哟
Oh, right, Inspector, I'll share something juicy with you.
对了 警部 告诉你一桩好事
The mahjong tiles represent an elevator.
麻将其实是指电梯
An elevator?
电梯？
Ow...
好疼…
There were altogether 9 people staying on the sixth floor of that hotel.
酒店六楼住了9个人
Aside from Nanako-san and Mizutani, all other seven were killed.
除开奈奈子小姐和水谷本人 其余7人全被杀害了
Then just who will be the final victim?
余下一人是谁？
Oh, I know.
我知道
This is chouzu, isn't it?
这是叫洗手水吧
Right, you sure know a lot!
对啊 您知道的挺多的嘛
But I don't know what to do with this dipper.
可是我不晓得怎么弄
Oh, yeah? Let me show you, then.
是吗 我教你吧 看好喽
What?
什么？
The location of the stars?
星星的位置？
The seven crime scenes represent locations of Polaris and the six stars in the Big Dipper.
北极星和北斗七星中的六颗星表示着七宗犯罪现场
Hold on.
等等
It's true. They are not just similar.
确实 不只是相似
They perfectly align with the actual photo of the stars.
与实际的星星照片重叠着看 几乎一致
What a perfectionist, our killer!
凶手挺一丝不苟的
The mahjong tiles and the letters all represent Polaris and the Big Dipper.
同样不管麻将还是字母 都表示北极星和北斗七星
The 1-pin and 7-pins all indicate the shape of Polaris and the Big Dipper.
一筒和七筒表示北极星和北斗七星的形状
And the letters represent stars from the Ursa constellations,
字母就是用于标记各个星星的希腊文字
and are short for the full spelling of α、β、γ、δ、ε、ζ、η in Greek. (Α、Β、Γ、Δ、Ε、Ζ、Η)
α、β、γ、δ、ε、ζ、η的大写 （Α、Β、Γ、Δ、Ε、Ζ、Η）
So, Haibara...
灰原
The location of the remaining Big Dipper star is unseen. I'll pull it out right now.
余下的北斗七星 就是看不见的位置 我马上调出来
Thank you!
拜托你了
There it is.
有了
Shiba Park, in Minato District.
港区芝公园一带
The person who sent the "Help!" message should be near that oak tree.
发送求救信息的人应该就在前面那棵栎树附近
We can't just sit back and do nothing.
我们不能袖手旁观
That's right!
对的
Detective Boys,
少年侦探团
let's go!
出发
A boy with glasses just came and asked about Mizutani-kun
水谷和奈奈子小姐的事 大概两个小时前
and Nanako-san two hours ago.
有个眼镜少年来问过啊
A boy with glasses?
眼镜少年？
Yeah. He said he was Detective Mouri's assistant.
是啊 说是毛利侦探的助手
This is what Mizutani-san said, correct?
那么 水谷先生是这么说的吧？
"There are eight people I can't forgive. Now, only one remains."
“不能原谅的人有八个 现在还剩一个”
Yes.
对的
What happened? Did Mizutani-kun...
发生什么事了 是不是水谷…
Nothing. Just asking.
没什么 问问而已
What?
什么
You mean our suspect plans to kill another?
那就是说凶手还要再杀一个人？
Yes. I'm afraid so. And Conan-kun came here earlier as well.
嗯 估计如此 还有 听说柯南也来过这里
Conan-kun?
柯南？
No!
没有啊
How could I send a little boy to do that?
我怎么可能让这种小屁孩去做这种事的
Then who else could it be? Could it be Kudo-kun?
那到底是谁 不会是工藤吧
Superintendent, is it safe to say that Kosuke Mizutani is the culprit?
警视 那凶手就是水谷浩介了
I think it's a fair assumption.
是啊 八九不离十
But who's his next target? And where is he gonna do the deed?
可是 还剩下谁 下一个案发现场又在哪儿呢
Nana...
奈奈
Kousuke!
浩介
Oh, no!
真是的
Can I try again?
再来一次嘛
I'm so excited!
我很期待哦
This is our first trip together!
我还是第一次和浩介旅游呢
Kousuke!
浩介
Nana! Nana! Let me go!
奈奈 奈奈 放开我
Nana's in there! Nana! Nana!
奈奈还在里面 奈奈 奈奈
Nana...
奈奈…
Okay.
好的
I'll try to look for them. Thanks!
我也试试找些线索 谢谢
Tsuburaya-kun hasn't gone home?
圆谷还没回来吗
It's 7:00 p.m. already. Where could those three be?
都七点了这三个人去哪儿了啊
I tried to reach them through their Detective Badges, but no answer.
用侦探徽章呼叫他们也没反应啊
Professor, do you think they...
博士 难道说他们…
Hello?
喂
Sawamura-san?
啊 泽村先生
Yes? Mizutani-kun and Nanako-san's hobby?
嗯？ 水谷和奈奈子的爱好？
Yes. Was it stargazing?
嗯 会不会是看星星呢
That's right.
对啊
He said he chose to live here because it's close to the observatory.
他说过住在这里是因为离天文台近
As I thought.
果然
Of all the stars,
星星之中
they loved Polaris and the Big Dipper the most
他们两个人最喜欢北极星和北斗七星
for the beautiful shape of the Big Dipper,
北斗七星的美妙形状
and Polaris shining right above the north pole.
和北极星常年在正北闪耀的身影
I think the stars were like a love token to them.
看了那星星 他们两人才确认了自己的爱吧
But a kid like you
这些跟你这个小孩子说
wouldn't understand.
你也弄不明白的啊
Thanks!
谢谢
The place where is closest to the stars would be...
说起这附近离星星最近的地方
Good evening!
晚上好
I'm currently at Tokyo Tower, where the Tanabata Fair is being held.
我现在来到了正在举办七夕祭典的东都塔
Though it's cloudy today, visitors wearing yukatas are still swarming to be here
虽然今天天气不太好 但由于七夕祭典将在今晚结束
since it's the last night of the fair.
穿着和服的游客们已经陆陆续续聚集到这里了
Next is our weather forecast for tonight and tomorrow.
接下来为大家介绍今晚到明天的天气情况
There's a high chance of rain in the Tokyo area around 10:00 tonight.
东京地区今晚10点以后开始降雨
Thunderstorms are expected elsewhere...
预计一些地方会有雷雨…
Onee-san!
姐姐
How may I help you, little boy?
什么事 小朋友
Could you watch this for me?
这个能帮我拿一下吗
I sure can. But are you all by yourself?
嗯 可以啊 不过你一个人吗
When I went to the bathroom,
我去厕所的时候
my dad and my younger brother left without me. Can you believe that?
爸爸和弟弟先走了 太过分了
Hitomi-chan, your yukata is so pretty!
小瞳 你的浴衣真漂亮啊
So is yours!
你的也很可爱啊
How about the four of us taking a picture?
我们四个一起照个相吧
The more the better!
多拍些 拍好多好多
Here we go. Ready?
那我拍了 准备
Cheese!
茄子
Have we been here before?
刚才经过这儿了吗
Did we take the wrong path?
路…走错了吧
I'm starving! Let's go home.
肚子饿死了 我们回去吧
No! We must find him ourselves!
不行 我们绝对要靠自己找到
That's right! Don't you want to solve a case without Conan-kun's help for once?
没错 你难道不想趁柯南不在的时候自己破一次案吗
I do.
想
But we can't seem to find that oak tree...
但是 找不到麻栎树啊
Oh, I know!
啊 对了
We can let this beetle show us the way!
让这位独角仙君告诉我们吧
Beetles usually fly towards the tree with the same sap.
独角仙一般都飞向产生同样树液的树
That way!
那边
Do we have to run?
得用跑的啊…
Through our investigation, we have identified the suspect,
调查结果 已查出犯罪嫌疑人
and have determined that it's highly possible he'll commit another murder.
并发现他可能还有一件命案在身
However, we know neither the whereabouts of the suspect nor the location of his next crime.
可是 嫌疑人的住所和犯罪现场还不知道在哪儿
Any thoughts, people?
有谁想到什么没有
Damn! While we are waiting here...
可恶 在这里等着的时候
Someone's probably being killed out there.
可能有人已经被干掉了
Found it! The oak tree!
找到了 麻栎树
Huh? There's another one!
咦 还有一只
Could it be also taped up?
说不定也贴着胶带
A little higher!
还差一点
It's taped, just like we expected.
果然贴着胶带呢
It must be there.
一定是那里
The one who seeks help must be in there.
需要帮助的人一定是在那里
I guess.
应该吧
But it looks a little creepy.
但是 有点毛骨悚然啊
I feel like something's coming.
嗯 感觉有什么东西要出来似的
Don't say that!
别说了
As expected, at a place like this, the stars sure look much more amazing!
哦 果然到了这里 看到的星星很漂亮呢
That one's Polaris, and that's the Big Dipper!
那个是北极星 那些是北斗七星
Huh? That shape...
嗯？ 那个形状
Where have I seen it?
好像在哪里…
What? Polaris and the Big Dipper?
什么 北极星和北斗七星？
Ouch! So you are saying the crime scenes represent Polaris and the Big Dipper?
疼死了 也就是说犯罪现场指的是北极星和北斗七星咯
I'm sure, Inspector!
不会错的 警部
You are the detective from earlier.
啊 刚才的那位刑警 是的
So, Mizutani-san and Honjue-san's hobby
那么水谷先生和本上小姐的兴趣
was stargazing? Thanks!
是观察星空了？ 谢谢
Superintendent.
警视
The final star from the Big Dipper matches the location of Shiba Park.
与北斗七星剩下的一颗星对应的位置是芝公园
Good work! Megure, secure an emergency warrant for Kosuke Mizutani and wait for further orders here.
好 目暮赶紧通缉水谷浩介 然后在这里待命
The rest of you, head over to Shiba Park! Hurry!
剩下的人去芝公园 动作快
Yes, sir!
是
What the...
什么啊
Don't scare me like that!
别吓我嘛
What do you mean?
什么什么啊
You shouldn't be hanging around here at this hour.
这样是不行的 玩到这个时间都不回家
We are not here for fun.
我们可不是在玩
We are trying to rescue someone.
是来帮人的
The one who used the beetles to send those S.O.S messages!
帮助用独角仙来求救的人
Whatever your reason is, you head home now. Your parents must be worried about...
总之先回去 家长们都很担心的
Not so fast.
先不要急
Huh?
嗯？
They can go home after we respond to that message.
先回复那条信息后再回去也可以吧
Thank you!
谢谢
I'll take it.
我来接
Sorry, if you would.
真不好意思 拜托了
Hello, this is Takagi's cell. Oh, Agasa-san.
喂 这是高木的电话 啊 阿笠先生
We are a little busy right now.
现在有点离不开手
Sorry to bother you, but please hear me out.
抱歉这么忙还打搅你 能听我说下吗
This may sound strange, but...
其实有件怪事
The Beatles? Could it be...
甲壳虫乐队？ 难道是…
Okay. I'll be right there.
好的 我这就去询问
Please find a safe place and hide.
你们赶快躲到安全的地方去
Takagi-kun, we need to stop by Beika Forest.
高木 朝米花森林开
But...
但是…
Don't worry. I'll take full responsibility.
没关系 出什么事的话我负责
Alright. But let me take that responsibility.
那好吧 不过我来负责
Huh? Which way?
喂 喂 是哪边
I don't know.
不知道
To the left.
左边
Got it.
是
Conan-kun went to the TV tower?
诶 柯南去了电视塔？
Yes. I saw him entering Tokyo Tower by himself.
嗯 我看见他一个人进了东都塔
It was around 8:00 p.m.
8点左右吧
I see.
是吗
Don't worry, though. He'll come home soon.
不过 你不用担心 他马上就会回来的
But his cell phone has been off.
但是他的手机一直关机
Still no answer. Superintendent, Takagi and Sato won't pick up.
不行啊 管理官 高木和佐藤都不接电话
Then let's start without them.
不管他们了
Mizutani should be hiding somewhere around here.
好 水谷应该潜伏在这附近
Split up, and arrest him as soon as you find him.
分开找 找到后就立刻逮捕他
Yes, sir!
是
It's cloudy today. You can't see them, can you?
因为阴天所以看不见吧
The stars you and Nanako-san loved,
水谷先生你和奈奈子小姐最喜欢的
Polaris and the Big Dipper.
北极星和北斗七星
Little boy...
小朋友
Oh, this visitor...
啊 您是说这位客人啊
You saw him?
见过吗
He visited the tower after-hours several times, so I remember him.
是啊 他好几次在闭馆的时候来咨询过 所以我记得
He went up to the viewing platform alone around 7:00 p.m.
大概是7点左右 一个人上了瞭望台
You're that assistant of Detective Mouri's, aren't you?
你是那个毛利侦探的助手吧
Sort of.
算是吧
It's too bad, huh?
不过真遗憾呢
To have come so close to the sky and not be able to see the stars.
难得来到离天空这么近的地方却看不见星星
No.
不
I can see them...
我能看见
whenever and wherever...
无论何时何地
I can see those stars.
都能看到那些星星
What? On the viewing platform?
什么 上了瞭望台？
Yes. This lady saw him go up there.
是的 这位女士说她看到了
Did you see him leave?
看到他出来了吗
No, not yet.
不 没有看到
Good. There's no doubt that our suspect is still on the platform
好 从嫌疑人在瞭望台这一点上看
and waiting for the target to walk into his trap.
肯定是叫谁去那里然后实施其罪行
Let's move! Arrest the suspect and protect the victim.
现在开始突进 逮捕嫌疑人保护受害者
The suspect may be armed. Stay alert!
嫌疑人应该持有凶器 都给我机灵点
Please keep the interior lighting as it is.
里面的照明请保持原样
Copy that.
遵命
Let's go!
走
Yes, sir!
是
Mizutani-san.
水谷先生
Are you going to kill yourself after finishing the wine?
你是想喝完酒后 就自杀吗
"There are eight people I can't forgive. Now, only one remains."
“不能原谅的人有八个 现在还剩一个”
The one that still remains is you, right?
那个剩下的人 就是你自己吧
Wh-What's going...
干…干什么
I understand the shock and the anger you felt when you learned how Nanako-san died.
我能明白当你知道她离开人世时的惊愕与愤怒
That's why you went to the hotel in Kyoto and investigated those seven people, right?
所以你到京都的酒店去调查了那七个人的情况
It's just as you said.
正如你所说的那样
If I hadn't visited my friend on that day two years ago,
两年前的那天 要是我没有去见朋友
Nana wouldn't have died.
就不会让她死掉
When I think of that, I can't forgive myself.
一这么想我就不能原谅我自己
But you can't commit suicide! It means you'll be killing...
但是自杀可不行 自杀是要杀掉自…
I know that...I do know that...
我知道 虽然我都知道…
But I can no longer bear to live in a world without Nana.
可我不能忍受活在没有她的世界里
Besides,
而且
I'll get a death sentence anyway.
我反正也是死刑
You won't!
不会变成死刑的
Why?
什么
Because you didn't kill anybody!
因为你一个人都没有杀死
Wasn't there someone else who asked a nice man like you to take guilt on yourself
我想 让如此温柔的你背负七条人命
and commit suicide in exchange for him killing those seven people?
并负罪自杀的 应该另有其人吧
I don't object to your desire to take responsibility for Nanko-san's death,
我并不反对你 对于她的死感到要负起全部责任
but the one that person really hates and wishes to kill
但是 那个人真正憎恨并想杀掉的
is actually you, Mizutani-san.
其实是你哦
It's because
因为
you were the one who took away his beloved sister.
你是夺走他所爱的妹妹的人
Isn't that right,
对吧
Nanako-san's elder brother,
奈奈子小姐的哥哥
Kazuki Honjue-san?
本上和树先生
Onii-san! What are you doing here?
哥哥 你怎么会在这里
Bastard, you have no right to address me that way!
你个臭小子没资格这么叫我
What?
什么
Kid,
小子
how did you know I did it?
你怎么知道是我做的
It made no sense, no matter how I looked at it.
我怎么也不能理解
If Mizutani-san was the culprit,
如果他是犯人的话
the logic behind choosing the positions of Polaris and the Big Dipper as the crime scenes
以北极星和北斗七星的位置来选择犯罪现场的那种心理…
would defile his precious stars, now wouldn't it?
这可是会玷污自己最喜欢的星星的 不是吗
Therefore, I thought this may have been
所以 我想 这可能是
a plan someone else had come up with to make him a scapegoat.
有人为了让他顶罪而想出的办法
When I realized that, everything came together.
这么一来 一切都说得通了
Moreover, the culprit, who precisely adapted the positions of Polaris and the Big Dipper
而且犯人将北极星与北斗七星准确地对在地图上
to the map and used them for crime scenes, is clearly a perfectionist.
并作为犯罪现场的人 定是个很完美主义的人
But the sign on Mizutani-san's apartment door
但是水谷先生公寓门上的门牌
was tilted and written in scrawl.
字有点歪也不是很好看
The phone number written on your name card, however,
在这一点上 你写在名片上的电话号码
was in very neat handwriting. There was even a faint pencil line to ensure the writing was straight.
字体整齐干净 为了避免写歪还用铅笔淡淡地划了条线
And inside your notebook, the names and addresses of those who sent flowers
你的记事本里面送花人的名字和住址
were carefully recorded.
也记得清清楚楚的
All of this undeniably showcases your perfectionist personality.
这也显示出你的性格严谨吧
Just who are you exactly?
喂 你到底是什么人
Conan Edogawa, a detective.
江户川柯南 是个侦探
Thank you for coming!
辛苦了
Agasa-san, where are the other kids?
阿笠先生 其他孩子呢
Their parents took them home. I'll show you the way.
都被他们父母领回去了 我带你们去吧
Please do.
拜托了
Ai-kun, go wait in the car.
小哀 你就在车里等下
You were the one who told Mizutani-san how Nanako-san died, weren't you?
把奈奈子小姐的死亡经过告诉水谷先生的人就是你吧
Yes. That day when I heard that the artist Sumire Shindo was staying in the same hotel on the same floor,
是的 那天我听说画家新堂堇和他住在同一酒店的同一层
I went to her personal art exhibition to ask some questions.
于是便去了他的个人画展想找他问点事情
At that time, I happened to overhear Sumire and Ryuuzaki's conversation.
那时我碰巧偷听到了堇和龙崎的对话
So you passed on the information, along with your own lies, to Mizutani-san.
你把对话内容告诉了水谷先生 还夹杂着谎言
On the first anniversary of Nanako-san's death, everyone who had been on the 6th floor brought flowers.
在奈奈子小姐的一周年忌日时住在六层的人都送来了花
If it was because they felt guilty, only one or two might have come,
要是一两个人的话也许是抱着自觉有罪而送来的
but all seven came.
但是七个人全送了
The only possible reason was they wanted to express their gratitude,
那就只有为了表示感谢了
thanking her for allowing them to board the elevator.
谢谢她为了他们而把电梯让了出来
So, you are saying Nanako wasn't forced out, instead, she willingly...
那么 难道说奈奈子不是被赶出来的而是自愿的…
That's right. She was such a kind girl.
没错 她是个很善解人意的孩子
But still, even if she got off willingly,
但是 即便是她自己下来的
it doesn't change the fact that she died because the rest of them
也不能改变正是因为他们乘上了电梯
had all boarded that elevator!
而导致她去世的事实
Mizutani-san,
水谷先生
it's true that Nanako-san sacrificed herself to save the other seven. However, it's worlds apart from
奈奈子小姐确实代替那七个人而去世了 但是 同样是作替身
how he made you a scapegoat and commit suicide for his crimes.
和他让你代他负罪自杀比起来可是天壤之别
The difference is as great as that of a star in the sky and a stone rolling on the ground.
那差距 正如天上闪耀的繁星与随意堆放地面的小石头一般
Nana...
奈奈
I quit.
我不干了
What?
什么
I'm sorry. I won't kill myself.
对不起 我不想死了
This boy's words have brought me to my senses.
这个孩子的话让我清醒了
Mizutani!
水谷
And I'm sure that Nana in heaven
在天堂的她也一定
wouldn't want me to commit suicide either.
不希望我自杀
Please take this back. I no longer need this.
这个还给你 我已经不需要了
Please turn yourself in, onii-san.
请你自首 大哥
Damn!
可恶
Honjue-san.
本上先生
Those are the items you took from the seven victims, right?
那个是从七名被害人身上夺走的东西吧
You gave them to him so that they'd be considered as evidence of the murders
你告诉他拿着这个死掉的话就会变成杀人的证据
after he committed suicide, right?
然后交给了他对吧
Hmph, it's a good thing I came.
哼 果然来对了
When I heard that Detective Mouri was investigating, I rushed here fearing something'd go wrong.
听说毛利侦探在调查 我怕露馅所以才赶到这里
I lied to you because I was hoping you could take revenge on them.
我骗你是因为期待你去找他们复仇
But you didn't have the courage, so I decided to take it into my own hands.
但是你没有那个胆量 所以我才决定自己下手
That isn't courage, but merely self-satisfaction!
那不是胆量而是你的自我满足
Shut up!
你给我住嘴
Since Detective Mouri isn't here, you must have come here alone.
毛利侦探不在这里 也就是说你是一个人来的了
How dare you belittle me!
别瞧不起人
Did I make it in time?
赶上了吗
I'm Matsumoto from the Metropolitan Police Department.
我是警视厅的松本
Metropolitan Police Department?
警视厅？
Are you injured?
没受伤吧
No.
没有
Come with me to the station.
能来下署里吗
Damn it!
糟了
Shit!
妈的
Like I'd let you arrest me like this!
哪能被你们抓住
As I thought...
你果然是…
You are Irish, aren't you?
你是Irish吧
Police!
警察
Don't move!
不许动
As expected! Superintendent!
果然 管理官
Superintendent?
管理官？
Hang in there!
请振作点
Superintendent! Who locked you here?
管理官 您怎么在这里
The other Superintendent Matsumoto is a fake. He's been replaced!
那个松本管理官是假货 已被替换了
The superintendent was from The Beatles generation, but I never thought it'd really be him.
管理官和甲壳虫乐队是同一时代的 没想到真的是他啊
Hurry and contact Inspector Megure!
快跟目暮警部联系
Okay!
是
It's me. What's up?
是我 怎么了
We've been exposed. They know he's a fake.
暴露了 他们知道他是个假货了
Got it.
知道了
Vermouth...
Vermouth…
What? He really was here?
什么 果然来了吗
Yeah. He asked me to watch his skateboard, but he never retrieved it.
嗯 叫我帮他拿着滑板 他却不来取 正觉得奇怪呢
Could he be still inside?
该不会是还在里面吧
That's not possible.
那不可能
It would be disastrous if he were. He could run into that murderer!
真是那样的话就麻烦了 会跟杀人犯碰个正着的
M-Murderer?
杀…杀人犯？
The police are conducting a search inside right now.
现在警察正在里面搜查
Sonoko, wait here!
园子 你在这里等着
Wait, Ran!
等…等一下 小兰
Hey! Wait!
你 等一下
What did you do to the superintendent?
你把管理官怎么了
Did you...
难道说…
No. He's still alive.
不 他还活着
I need him to be my scapegoat, you know.
因为必须让他代替我当下犯人
I'm assuming that's the memory card containing the Organization's NOC list, no?
那个是装有组织间谍名单的记忆卡吧
Yeah, it is.
啊 是的
When did you find out I was a fake?
你从什么时候开始知道我是假的
Here's my thought. If Vermouth, the master of disguise, had sent someone else
大致能想到的是 如果不是精通易容的Vermouth
to infiltrate in her stead, it must be because the huge difference in body shape that made it impossible.
而是别人潜入的话 可能是因为体格相差太大不容易乔装
In that case, you were the first to come to mind.
这么考虑的话你就成了第一候补
I see. As expected, you are Shinichi Kudo indeed.
果然如此 不愧是工藤新一
Before matching the fingerprints, I still wasn't sure.
到指纹一致之前我都半信半疑
Have you reported this to your boss?
你已经向你们的BOSS汇报了吗
Nope. I haven't told anybody about this.
不 我还没跟任何人说过
Not even Gin?
也没有告诉Gin？
Yeah.
嗯
Do you remember Shinichi Kudo?
工藤新一 你忘了吗
I've killed too many people to remember every one of them.
被我干掉的人那么多 哪记得住
What about him, anyway?
那家伙怎么了
No. Nothing.
不 没什么
Hmph. Just focus on your own mission.
哼 总之你专注自己的任务就行
Why?
为什么
There was a time
他以前
when he shot a fellow member of the Organization that made a mistake.
将犯错了的组织成员射杀之后
He left the body to burn there at Haido City Hotel where it eventually turned to ashes.
还要把尸体放在起火的杯户城市酒店里 烧成一堆焦炭
That member was someone I respected like a father.
我曾把那名成员当作父亲一样敬仰
Haido City Hotel...
杯户城市酒店…
Pisco?
Pisco吗
You've investigated us thoroughly, haven't you?
哼 你连我们这边的事情也一清二楚啊
To have failed in killing Shinichi Kudo and in seeing through your true identity, he's made a huge oversight.
没能杀掉工藤新一 而且没能看穿你的真身是他的大失误啊
I'll be taking you to meet that person
我会把你带到那位先生面前
to make you a witness in order to overthrow that conceited and cold-blooded bastard.
作为让那个令人作呕冷血无情的人失势的证人
He's the only one who knows my real identity for now. As long as I can defeat him...
我的真实身份还只有这个男人知道 只要击败他…
But, with the tranquilizer out of action, there's only...
但是麻醉枪已不能用 剩下的…
Don't worry. I won't kill you. I'm just going to knock you unconscious.
放心 不会杀你 只是让你暂时失去知觉
Unless I bring you back alive,
不活着带回去的话
that person wouldn't believe that you are actually Shinichi Kudo.
那位先生也不会相信你是工藤新一吧
What is...
这是…
Detective Chiba? Detective Chiba? Are you okay?
千叶刑事 千叶刑事 没事吧
It seems he's just lost consciousness. I think the others are the same.
好像只是失去知觉了 大概其他人也是
Conan-kun!
柯南
Wait! Hey!
等下 你
Hey! Wait up!
你 等一下
Conan-kun!
柯南
Conan-kun! What happened?
柯南 怎么了
Ran-neechan...
小兰姐姐
Are you okay?
没事吧
Are you guys alright?
你们没事吧
Superintendent Matsumoto?
松本警视
Superintendent, bad news! The other officers downstairs were...
警视 不好了 下面其他的刑事们…
Attacked by the suspect, right?
被犯人袭击了是吧
What is it?
什么
Don't... Run...
不行 快逃…
What? What happened?
什么 怎么了
Run! It's him...
快逃 是他
What?
什么
You are not Superintendent Matsumoto, aren't you?
你不是松本警视吧
Don't!
不行
It's alright.
没关系
I can't avoid a bullet from a rifle like Kyougoku-san, but a pistol...
我虽然不能像京极先生那样躲得过步枪 但是手枪的话…
Ran, you know what?
小兰 你知道吗
The speed of a rifle bullet is about 1,000 meters per second.
步枪子弹的速度大概是每秒1000米
Compared to that, the speed of a pistol's bullet is only a third of that-roughly 350 meters a second.
与其相比 手枪子弹速度只有1/3 即每秒350米左右哦
What's so funny? You think you can dodge a bullet?
有什么奇怪的 你难道认为你能躲得开子弹吗
That's exactly it.
正是如此
Interesting! Then try it!
有意思 放马过来
What?
什么
Amazing!
真厉害
Nice move, young lady!
身手很不错啊 小姐
I forgot that you are a karate expert.
差点忘了 你可是个空手道高手啊
Ran!
小兰
You're making me wasting my energy here!
哼 让我这么费事
Ran, stay down!
小兰 别起来
Leave the rest to me! Just stay there!
剩下来的交给我 待在那儿别动
Damn!
妈的
Run! Go ahead!
逃吧 逃吧
It's more fun this way!
让我更加享受吧
Darn it!
可恶
What a pity! You almost got me!
可惜 就差一点呐
What? Are you done fighting now?
怎么了 玩儿完了吗
Good! There you go!
好的 就是这样
Let's end this game of cat-and-mouse, shall we?
让我们结束猫捉老鼠的游戏吧
Now the tables have turned!
形势逆转了呢
Crap!
靠
Now, hand over the memory card!
麻烦你把记忆卡给我吧
So, they are here!
来了吗
The tables have turned again!
哈 形势逆转…了呐
It's me.
是我
How did it go?
怎么样
Have you secured the memory card?
记忆卡拿到了吗
Yeah.
嗯
I can't see it clearly. Hold it out further.
我看不到你 再往前站点儿
Hmph...
切
That's right. A little more.
对 再往前一点
Now!
动手
Bingo!
中了
I wanted to shoot.
我想射的
Boss.
大哥
Look down.
看看下面
That's...
那是？
He has nowhere to run. Thanks for your service, Irish.
他已经逃不掉了 辛苦了 Irish
There's someone else down there.
还有一个人
Hey, stay with me! Hey!
喂 你撑着点 喂
You'll live! It's not fatal. I'll get you medical treatment
没事的 没打中要害 只要收拾掉那帮家伙后
once I've taken care of those people.
我马上给你治疗
I see now.
原来如此
No wonder Vermouth thinks so highly of you.
难怪Vermouth会看上你
Don't talk!
别说话
After you've recovered,
治好伤后还要让你说出
I still need you to reveal the true identity of your boss! So hang in there!
你们BOSS的真面目 所以给我做好准备
Irish!
Irish
Shinichi Kudo, don't stop going after them...
工藤新一 无论到什么时候 你都要追下去
Hmph! He used Irish as a shield!
切 居然拿Irish当挡箭牌
It'll be big trouble if we have to land. Use that!
降到下面就麻烦了 用那个
Roger!
收到
Damn!
可恶
Oh, no! Ran is still inside!
不好 小兰还在下面
He's out! Continue!
出来了 跟上
Boss, what do we do?
大哥 怎么办
Chianti, smoke him out!
Chianti 把他熏出来
Okay.
OK
Damn it! What now?
可恶 怎么办
Tear gas!
催泪弹
Here he comes!
出来了
Force him to the top!
逼他到上面
The mouse has been cornered. Go up. Attack from above! There'll be nowhere to hide!
哼 老鼠被逼到绝境了 上面 从上面瞄准 那样就没有死角了
Copy!
收到
Damn!
可恶
What do I do? At this rate, I'll be a sitting duck!
怎么办 这样下去就成瓮中之鳖了
Damn! What do I do?
可恶 怎么办
Now... Let me see your face!
嘿 让我拜见下尊容吧
He... He jumped!
飞…飞下来了
He'll accept his fate of no escape, huh?
哼 知道自己跑不掉了就自投罗网了吗
Go!
去吧
We've been hit!
被打败了
Hold on!
等等
What happened?
怎么样了
I... I'm losing control!
不…不能控制了
No choice! Retreat!
没办法 撤退
Copy!
收到
What...
什么…
Who was it...
是什么人…
As expected of the Silver Bullet. He's good.
不愧是银色子弹 真有一手
And then "bang," I was totally out!
那个 突然间砰的一声 我就昏过去了
Thank God no one was hurt!
没有人受伤真是太好了
I'm sorry!
真对不起
Well, then, Ran-chan.
那么小兰
I'll inquire as to the details another day. Until then, thank you!
详情改天再问你吧 到时拜托了哦
Sure.
好的
I'll arrange for a car to take you home now. Please wait a moment.
现在我给你安排辆车送你回去 等一下哦
Thank you very much!
谢谢你
Are you really alright?
你真的没事吗
Yes.
嗯
Oh, I'll get you something to drink.
对了 我去拿点喝的过来
You don't have to.
啊 不用了
Just wait here.
别客气了
Thank you!
谢谢你
Ran-neechan.
小兰姐姐
Shinichi-niichan said that the case has been solved.
新一哥哥说已经没事了 案件已经解决了
Speaking of Shinichi...
说起来新一…
About that, he said he had another case.
啊 那个… 他说有别的案件
Eh? He left abruptly again?
啊 又自说自话走了吗
Hmm. And...
嗯 还有…
I'm sure he said something like, "don't tell anyone about it."
反正是说不要跟别人提他的事之类的吧
Oh, right! He also said it was alright for you to call now.
啊对了对了 他说现在可以给他打电话了
Alright for me to call?
可以打电话了？
Oh, no, something like, "please call me."
啊 不是 可能是说请你给他打过去…
Well, just hearing his voice is good enough.
即便只能听到他的声音也好啊
Besides,
而且
voice aside, there are people who can only see each other once a year.
别说是声音了 好像还有一年只能见一次的人呢
Seems that they didn't find any bodies in the debris of that helicopter crash.
从坠落的直升机里好像没发现任何尸体
Yeah.
是啊
All of them must have escaped before the explosion.
爆炸前所有人都逃出去了吧
And in the end, we still didn't get to uncover Irish's true identity.
结果还是没能搞清Irish的真实身份
The police didn't come across anything either, did they?
警方好像也什么都没掌握到
I couldn't possibly tell them, anyway.
我又不能去说
But who would've thought that he was confined in such a place for 10 days...
不过 没想到他被监禁在那种地方十天…
I heard Superintendent Matsumoto didn't see the face of the person who kidnapped him.
听说松本管理官也没有看到绑架自己的犯人的脸
Anyway, it was all thanks to those kids that he was rescued.
总之能救出他倒还是那些孩子的功劳呢
Yeah.
是啊
Irish died before he could even reveal the hiding place.
因为Irish还没来得及说出囚禁地点 就已经死了
Irish...
Irish…
Shinichi Kudo, don't stop going after them...
工藤新一 无论到什么时候 都要追下去
I will do just that until I take you all down!
我一定会追到底的